# Zane O'Dell

zanemodell@gmail.com | +1 (989)-430-9397 | 341 Rampart Way, East Lansing, MI 48823 | Portfolio | LinkedIn

# **Profile**

I am a Computer Science senior at Michigan State University with a minor in Game Design and Development.

I have a passion for creating refined and enjoyable experiences through intuitive user interfaces and smooth gameplay systems.

# School/Personal Projects

PizzaKai ☑ 04/2023 - present

Producer, UI Programmer, and Gameplay Programmer

- Implemented weapon systems using a modular system that was expanded upon for each individual weapon, creating a unique but effective system that made weapons easy to prototype and develop
- Implemented UI functionality through information transfer and responsive updates regarding player information and game story beats
- Planning on showcasing at Youmacon 2023

Ragnaracket ☑ 02/2023 - 03/2023

Producer, UI Programmer, and Gameplay Programmer

- Created the character controller by utilizing 2D style movement in a 3D environment, prioritized responsive movement and intuitive controls
- Implemented UI elements such as a volley counter as visual feedback to the player of their success in the game
- Undertook a producing role which demanded team-wide organizational and communication skills

Portfolio Website ☑ 01/2023 - present

Front-end Developer

• Learned the principles of the React framework through creating a portfolio website, which increased knowledge of web development frameworks

#### Professional Experience

**Auto Owners Insurance** 05/2023 - 08/2023

Claims Systems Developer

- Developed a feature that displayed certain claimant information only when necessary
- Developed a feature in which an error message disappeared if previously visible when user provided a valid file
- Gained experience in a professional team environment by communicating with teammates over Slack and Webex, making professional team-related work more familiar
- Became accustomed to workflow methods and software, such as JIRA and Confluence, which helped facilitate an agile development process

### Michigan State University

Computer Architecture Undergraduate Learning Assistant

• Assisted in teaching students with computer organization and architecture fundamentals, by helping them via in-person help rooms and answering questions in an online forum

09/2022 - 12/2022

East Lansing, MI

Lansing, MI

#### Education

#### Michigan State University

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Engineering; GPA: 3.8

Minor in Game Design and Development, Anticipated Graduation Date May 2024

09/2020 - 05/2024 East Lansing, MI

# Skills

• Unity • C# • C++ • Python

• TypeScript • Javascript • HTML • CSS

• Angular • React • Unreal Engine 5 • ARM Assembly

• Slack • GIT • Jira • Trello